all right hello and welcome it's June
28th 2024 we're here in quarterly Round
Table number two for this year welcome
to the active inference Institute we're
a participatory online Institute that is
communicating learning and practicing
applied active inference find us at some
of the links here this is recorded in an
archived live stream please provide
feedback so we can improve our work all
backgrounds and perspectives are welcome
and we'll follow video etiquette for
live streams and also I'll show this new
slide with some nice stable links that
will be good
signposts and stable ones
too so we're in our second quarterly
Round Table of a year there's going to
be three main sections First Institute
updates then we'll go to the to
organizational units and talk about
project scale updates and then look a
little bit towards the second half of
2024 first though anyone who wants to
unmute and just go ahead and introduce
say hi and and anything else you want to
begin
with I'll break the ice hi I'm Blue uh I
am really excited at um all of the
things that the Institute has
accomplished this quarter the fellows
program the Partnerships um and our
upcoming uh philanthropy program TBD
more
later I'll go next uh I'm John Bo one of
the new fellows this year so excited to
be joining The Institute in that
capacity and I guess there's more
later I'm Jean frer I'm also uh a
research fellow part of that first batch
and I'll Echo John's words that uh and
say I'm very excited uh to uh be in this
role and and and hope uh that um I will
be able to provide some good
value hi uh I'm Andrew um I'm an intern
with the Institute I've been involved
with a a few different projects on and
off over the past maybe year especially
helping facilitate the textbook group
whenever I can looking forward to that
uh coming back up in a couple of weeks
and uh yeah looking forward to seeing
the rest of the developments with
Institute seeing it
grow okay good next yeah yeah real quick
uh yes so my name is Holly grim and I'm
a second uh member of the scientific
scientific Advisory board for the second
year I'm working with the on the journal
project with Alex and U right now I'm
kind of building you know a set of
Utilities in Python and Russ to help
transcribe all of uh Daniel's amazing uh
YouTube videos and sessions and uh
trying to so we can eventually create a
a way of you know using a retrieval
augmented generation created an llm
agent or uh you know chat with with all
of these these doc you know these uh
sessions that um have been recorded so
thanks okay let me jump in I'm Alex uh
one of the officers of the Institute
also into Journal project and some hours
so great to see everyone let's have a
this round
table awesome okay okay first going over
some Institute scale updates on the
digital infrastructure side as the
stable links are kind of the tip of the
iceberg of we'll be looking and have
been making some updates to the
accessibility and usability of the
different services at The
Institute one of those stable links will
take you to
ecosystem. active influence. Institute
and at this page which again the end
point may vary will look to develop and
really communicate more about what is
the active inference Institute what is
the ecosystem how are they articulated
how how have they begun and changed
through time structurally and all these
different ways and so one useful piece
of information at that resource is kind
of like a menu or uh kind of continence
of the ecosystem and another exciting
announcement is that we'll be doing an
updating process on our
2023 Institute ecosystem paper so it'll
be very fun there will be a lot of
multimedia and Collective exploration
and refinements of big impactful visions
and things that people are motivated and
excited and already working on and so to
be able to clarify that within the
second half of the year in a certain way
and also understand what what is the
role of different functionalities in the
ecosystem at The Institute so this will
be a fun process in the second half of
the year that we'll share more
information about but it'll involve all
aspects of The Institute anyone want to
add anything
here okay so thanks to the officers the
board of directors who had their second
quarterly meeting several weeks ago and
to the Scientific Advisor board who
completed their first phase of
activities and we'll head into phase two
soon at the website there's more
information about these positions for
now thanks to everybody who's been
carrying it on this
quarter one of the really exciting new
aspects and programs at The Institute in
the last few weeks was the introduction
of the research fellows program so
perhaps JF and then John what is it in
how you're seeing it and what you'll
like to do with
it I I'll go ahead um well I I've I've
been uh conducting a a research project
here at the institute for the last uh
two years this now called the symbolic
co uh cognitive robotics
project and this project will now
continue uh under the umbrella of
research
fellowship and uh what I I hope to to
gain from this is uh increased uh uh
participation involvement exposure which
uh uh will bring in unanticipated
rewards uh I'm sure it's already
started uh and what I hope to provide is
uh to use Daniel's words is increased
epistemic value uh of my of my
research and uh hope to be able to uh
present on a more regular basis uh my
progress and and hoping that the
Institute will benefit from providing me
this this this increased
exposure um again my name is John Bo and
uh my effort is focused on uh cognition
in the large group setting so how how
can a group of say 100 thousand people
or a million people come together in
some kind of online ecosystem to make
decisions uh uh discuss uh events uh uh
and make other cognitive and perform
other cognitive processes how does that
happen efficiently how can everyone have
their Rich input heard uh U and the
group in my in my work the group might
be just a a group of people focused on
some issue or it could be actually a
something more formal a formal group
like a city
or U even a nation perhaps one day so
that's that's what I'm working on I hope
that's will be uh productive and
useful awesome and and Anna Pereira will
share more about her work in the weeks
to
come this is an exciting program it's as
with all things on a rolling application
basis so reach out if you have any
questions or to complete the
application that's about individuals who
are learning and applying active
inference also on the
interorganizational scale we have begun
the part ships program so these are
structured relationships between the
Institute and other
organizations and we expect and prefer
this will look like many things already
in the one accepted application which
will'll announce in the coming weeks and
several that are in progress It's really
interesting and useful even already to
explore where people are at and
understand how to respectfully and
appropriately have partnership anyone
want to add any comments or or thoughts
on
this all right and one major piece of
news from the last several weeks was
receiving the 501c3 or USA tax exempt
status so the link donate. active
inference do Institute is one place that
will develop into an on-ramp for
providing different kinds of of
financial
support we're definitely looking to
learn and to collaborate and to
understand how we can support the
sustainability of The Institute and
through that support the accessibility
and utility of active inference anyone
want to make any comments on
this I just wanted to thank Fred Frank
who was our um they were our pro bono
attorney that really worked hard over a
long time to uh help us achieve this
status thank you blue important to
mention too thank you a
lot on different digital
platforms we continue being active and
growing bit by
bit as we turn now to the middle of this
Round Table where we'll look at project
scale updates and through systems
engineering and Alex's in particular
vision for understanding this
hierarchical nested nature of our
ecosystem organization and project-based
teams in 2024 following Chris fields's
information physics as information
processing uh course we decided to jump
in full F to the prepare measure
Paradigm so here's Alice and Bob or
system A and B communicating and this
could be communication of a thing
through time could be across a
Communications interface and so we
thought about different ways to use
active inference to learn and apply
active inference and saw a connection
here between the project-based teams and
organizational approach and to connect
that to the quantum active conference
prepare measure cycle and so it's only
been half of a year however it's been a
very interesting Dynamic already with
quite quickly in the beginning of the
year and then also continuing people
submitted project preparations and and
updated whether it was a Institute
project that was just kind of reentering
the system or projects from people we
knew projects from people we didn't know
various people completed these project
proposal forms and their projects were
listed as active and then just in the
last several days with many people's
measure forms being
submitted the rest of this round table
and the newsletter which is basically
the same information broadly same
updates is prepared essentially in a
copypaste format from what people have
reported at the project scale in their
own learning so this is really exciting
to see
not just the Cod of forms capacity the
kind of digital affordances that can be
implemented various ways but really the
fact that people want to and are
submitting more and more parts of their
experience on projects of their own
other projects and so on so I look
forward to this continuing to increase
and across multiple scales new and
creative uses of the preparation and the
measure
it's a really just exciting way to kind
of not just learn by doing but be doing
by doing and that's pretty cool with
active inference any general thoughts on
this or or anything Quantum
active uh yeah let me add something I
want to say that from very beginning we
we tried to appli First some first
principles into organization development
and process development starting from
active inference systems approach and
now even Quantum information processing
and it's possibly could look simple like
two two new entities prepare measurement
forms but I believe as they are based on
really like real physics that the
current state of the physics it will
bring into organization and to
Institute a great eff to develop based
on
it thank you Alex very well said anyone
else okay we'll just jump into projects
so first from the edu active which is
education organizational unit just to
give a snapshot and separate out the
projects into those hosted at The
Institute and those happening in the
broader ecosystem first in the broader
ecosystem Susan Hasty's research on
negotiation
affordances Ana Magdalena ortado work on
UNIF fysica we'll get to these updates
Pablo FM and others with num minia and
shaa Dobson Hector manrique and Dean and
others in the math art conversation so
those are projects that facilitators
have just stepped up to do and several
of the core educational projects at The
Institute the active inference ontology
audiovisual production textbook group
and the journal so let's hear a little
bit more about those
projects on the textbook group cohort 6
will continue with the second half of
the book and cohort 7 will begin from
the beginning of the book on July 15th
it'll be a fun go around again it'll
have some classic and familiar
characters like the ACT INF onology and
using different kinds of question-based
methods for Learning and asking fun
collaborative discussions there'll also
be some different elements it'll be on a
three-week rhythm we'll do two weeks per
chapter and then each of the cohorts
will have a third
week in the second half of the book that
third week will be more about applying
active inference looking more at the
code which is what the second half of
the book is about and in the third week
of the first half of the book we'll
Explore More what that might look like
and also with collaboration with Andrew
pendin we will have some additional math
learning collaborations and there's a
lot of fun continued work on the
textbook so it'll be fun to have have
had that month or two off jump back into
second half of the year with a textbook
group any other textbook group
thoughts all right in production we've
had some fun videos over the last couple
months if anyone um wants to call out
any specific live stream that they
participated in or or viewed and thought
was
fun go for it there was nine guest
streams there was an art
stream six
insights uh
excellently planned and executed by
Darius and including the Ian mcchrist
surprise which is I think happening
concurrently there were several math art
streams that were very creative and very
exciting we did a paper based live
stream series number 57 which was the
first in a few months on the paper by
par friston and zidan active data
selection that was extremely relevant
and a really promising direction for the
development of active inform
and there was an or stream with Nathan
Schneider on governable Spaces that was
also really cool so anyone want to add
any other
thoughts okay on other updates from edu
active from the fundamentals of active
inference project we concluded a phase
of work with sanjie in his incredible
Odyssey of the fundamentals of active
inference we we concluded essentially
weekly meetings since the beginning of
2023 and we look forward to next phases
for for that project and work Anna
Magdalena orta reports from UNIF fysica
project and I'm sure we'll hear more
from their work Susan Hasty's weekly
meetings also came to a excellent
closure in the action research on
Collective foraging
project as she heads into some new
programs and directions for the work
Pablo FM reported from the num minia
project from one of the
symposia there was a demonstration of an
active inference game in an escape room
in the same Spirit has been built which
is kind of fun and people can check it
out in the newsletter where everything
is for all the links and all that from
the math art project so kind of in the
same Forest as the live streams from
math art but part of the broader
conversation Bert who continues to do
awesome work in the internship made a
short report that I know there's so much
more to say on and from the journal
project Alex and Holly want
to share anything or what what is
exciting from
Journal yeah so I kind of mentioned it
already that I'm interested in uh doing
retrieval augmented generation and so um
I was able to get um you know a huge uh
one tbte um disc from you Daniel and and
take all those uh videos and transcribe
them uh using a local whisper model on
my um on my server here at home so so
that was nice in terms of not having to
pay too much money out to get those
transcripts done by um you know third
party uh tooling so and uh yeah and
using open Source models so we can start
to uh you know make use of those
transcripts and I'm pretty excited about
that
so Alex anything you want to
add no great
thanks thank you all right to
Reiner all right just kind of
snapshotting what projects we have that
are active so essentially those that
have provided us a measurement and any
that aren't here can be brought back on
by
measurement from the
ecosystem um Jeremy Cooper and others
have been working on active inference
account of belief updating in
PTSD Michael Carl and others have been
working on the active inference model of
translations for language JF mentioned
the symbolic cognitive Robotics and
shager ramen has continued work in
writing on the humanity story of
Uncertain self
at The Institute we continue faster and
slower and differently on knowledge
engineering and seeing different
opportunities for the kinds of knowledge
engineering approaches that might
benefit active inference in the
ecosystem active block frence combining
active inference with the cad CAD
systems engineering framework by block
science is continuing to proceed on a
few different directions
and then one of our major activities in
Reiner has been the RX infer Learning
and Development Group so just to sort
of contextualize this in active model
stream
4.1 implementing active inference by
message passing in a factor graph from
August
[Music]
2021 I looked back to see this
presentation by bias lab and see what
they had planned to have done for the
future of applying reactive message
passing which at that point was a
research Advanced on top of the factor
graph formalism the 40 Factor graph
constrainted 40 Factor graph and so on
had enabled better Logistics to go from
the basian graph to the variational
message passing and then this reactive
feature was getting added in and so it's
just really interesting to see how they
laid out forny laab 2.0 forny lab. JL
2.0 and
then come
2024 we're having great times in the
engineering channel in Discord and on a
lot of people's personal projects cass's
work at learnable Loop people interested
in using RX and fur at different kinds
of hackathons and different projects and
then also a a crossover moment with the
textbook group was with the help of some
members of the bias laab here's one of
the early figures from the 2022 textbook
of the frog jumping out of the hands or
the something jumping out of the hand or
not and then here's what the app model
block for RX and fur looks like and so
seeing this kind of an isomorph mapping
between the visual representation the
code the iCal formalisms the art all
these different edges that's what kind
of the fun has always been suggested to
be so to start to see the operational
improvements in reactive message passing
and the way that the the groups and the
developers involved in this project are
closing the gap between what is
suggested in principle and in computer
science proof of example and taking it
to just an amazing engineering informed
level anyone want to add anything on
aroner I want to say that it's really
great development and um it's um good
that we organized with group of people
who are beginners on learning in that
toolbox and I believe that toolbox which
uh should provide affordance to build a
agents and Collective
agents
uh will be a base for some breakthrough
in artificial intelligence and possibly
we are putting some Cornerstone for
it thanks Alex and thanks to the the the
many participants who are just doing
awesome discussion in the engineering
Channel contributions to the Koda and to
to the GitHub
directly all right from the active
inference ontology project there have
been quite a few updates Dave Douglas as
always leading the V of birds has
produced two amazing open- Source works
that are almost like snapshots of really
broad ontological inquiries so first a
single author paper aligning spatial web
terms to Sumo which is in reference to
the itle e p287 4 standards draft and
working group connecting that to Sumo
which has always been this kind of
vision of incorporating multiple
ontologies including formal ones like
sumo and then also in a snapshot of our
primary active inference
ontology we had a number of authors join
this open- Source snapshot about
aligning the active inference ontology
to Sumo so starting to triangulate and
constellate multiple ontologies along
the way learning a lot about using
communicating languaging around them and
and different functionalities and niches
for different structures and visions of
onology so that kind of like meta
ontological active inference component
and also bringing the active inference
ontology in a in a connected way to
formality while also exploring in the
very same project um and and in kind of
other meetings and spaces more of the
the in formalizable ineffable components
so that's pretty cool to
see
any ontology
ideas just a short short note that it's
okay to have like M multiple sces
multiple scales of uh uh models and have
Meta Meta Meta
models
cool um all right and from other Reiner
updates
we have Andrew and JF so how about
Andrew and then JF if you want to add
any more what what have you been uh
working
on uh yeah and thanks for having me uh
so um yeah quick hearkening back to
other projects I've been working with
Jeremy Cooper on the updating uh belief
Dynamics uh it's a computational
Psychiatry project Focus ing on PTSD and
something I really appreciate about the
Institute is its way to kind of remotely
bring together uh a variety of you know
people and researchers of different
backgrounds that group includes a
computational
neuroscientist uh a clinical therapist
and then you have someone like me and
we're we're all learning kind of as
we're doing in order to try and recreate
something like the belief Dynamics of an
individual has PTSD in the direction of
developing developing treatments so uh
it's it's been a super valuable
experience as well as on and off working
with the RX and fer group as I continue
to develop my own ability to kind of
code uh active inference agents and
simulations so um so yeah here this
project uh active agents and active
inference approach to agent-based
modeling and the social sciences of be
giving that this year at the uh 10th
International Conference on
computational social science being held
at University of
Pennsylvania uh basically the tutorial
attempts to address a growing interest
in more cognitively complex agents to be
used in agent-based modeling as opposed
to just strict if then uh sort of Agents
if this happens then they necessarily do
this and so on uh giving them the
ability to make inferences and so I've
taken a lot of inspiration from um work
like uh your own uh work Daniel on the
inference project that was my first Fay
into like thinking okay I can model an
individual agent but what how do you
model multiple as they interact an
environment that changes which then
impacts them getting a better grasp of
differentiation between internal and
external
States um it's been great as well as
another uh paper by uh some folks from
the scientific Advisory board for the
Institute M alberene and Connor
Hines um which is also really great very
social science oriented uh work um so
I'm doing something in turn as kind of
they did uh I created a simulation that
recreates a common social science
paradigm time uh multiple agents working
in a network engaging in parallel
problem solving and it it using active
inference it it recreates the Dynamics
of the original Paradigm if you were to
run it through net logo or some other
common software but uh you can also look
under the hood at the agent's own
beliefs and I think that this could be
used potentially for policy uh
development
uh it could be used for you know if you
have students uh assigned a group
project how much do they actually learn
to rely upon themselves working in a
group as opposed to stealing their
neighbors answers um so interesting
stuff anyway kind over speaking here but
uh thanks for including this in the uh
in the talk here
so awesome cool and helping facilitate
the previous interval of the textbook
group too
and and with Ali on that too
JF sure uh so the uh symbolic cognitive
robotics project um asks the question um
what does it take at a minimum for a a
simple mobile robot to survive in a
world it knows initially very little
about so the focus is is in on learning
through engagement with uh an agent's
environment it focuses on the
development of agency uh in a robot
which starts with very little in terms
of uh cognitive constructs and
through engagement through acquisition
of experience grows a um a Society of
Mind a a collect
of simple cognition
actors uh which each one uh quite uh
specialized in terms of what it can
perceive and what it can do um and and
they all work together in the sense that
um a cognition actor Will through
observations of its
umelt uh generate synthesize beliefs
which will then become observations to
more abstract cognition actors so you
have this lad of belief
abstraction uh that is built up through
active engagement in the environment
through uh
learning what simple perceptions
mean uh learning what affordances there
are what can the robot do um and as the
robot grows its Collective of cognition
actors uh the conjecture is that it will
detect um
Trends and
uh how it's its its beliefs its more and
more abstract beliefs map uh homeostatic
signals am I doing something that
benefits my
survival in in my continued continued
survival so it's really a project about
um uh how a an agent learns its own
agency learns its affordances learns to
make sense of its
perceptions through more and more
elaborate beliefs um and and all of this
sense making is grounded in the survival
imperative now of course the the
physical robot is not mortal I mean I
can turn it off turn it back on it's
still there it's like your computer but
the Society of minded will grow through
its its its experiences through its
learning is itself mortal and I set up a
a an experimental environment such that
the robot as such as as a
minimum amount of time in order to grow
competencies at explor exporing and
foraging otherwise it expends its its
store of energy without ever
replenishing it so it needs to forge to
replenish it needs also to avoid
collisions because collisions are
delerious to its
Health it it it needs also to keep a
level of Engagement otherwise
it it it it it essentially Retreats away
from the environment so the all these
motivations
um uh activate this this this this um
Society of mine that the robot uh grows
over time and all I'm trying to do is
set up this mechanisms these mechanisms
and launch the robot and see if it can
grow it's it's it's make up its own mind
basically about the world it needs to
engage uh with so there are Notions of
collective intelligence there are
Notions of mortal Computing there are
Notions of uh grounded sense making uh
affordance
Discovery um there's also um a very big
nod uh to uh Emanuel Kant and it's in
his
epistemology because the the robot is is
needs to develop causal theories of its
perceptions how do I make how can I
predict what I will perceive next is is
very important so a very strong notion
of predictive processing based on the
discovery of causal Theory how do I make
sense uh of of the perceptions and the
actions that I that I that I engage into
how can it how can I predict what
happens next and and all these concepts
are are brought together in in in a
um in in in a hole that hopefully uh
leads to uh autonomous agency and really
simple Lego robots which brings in a
dimension of fun as well because these
robots are are really fun to build and
and fun to run um
and my hope is that not only does uh the
robot uh get to learn how to survive but
that we can observe its behaviors and
its OB in its visible States and subject
them to an active inference analysis and
be able to demonstrate that yes indeed
the robot uh reduces its variational
free energy and gets better at it over
time or not so it's it's a very fun
project and I uh
I I I I get a lot of uh uh input from
the community and uh I'm constantly fed
by all the material that the Institute
uh produces so it's um it's a very fun
thing to
do awesome thank you both for the
updates all right that'll be uh sorry
yeah go ahead please
please yeah as for Andre's work uh I
believe at some point it could be
integrated into social scient sciences
course somehow if it's interesting
possibly it's uh would be not not only
in our chapter in the course but also
somehow argument our chapters with some
computational approach
and
practice and I want to say big thanks
for JF for his continuous work on his
robotics projects it's really great and
really great to see its development
through the time thank you very
much thank you I agree with that anyone
else want to make
any comments on Reiner or
projects I'd ask a question to JF if I
if we have a second can you
just talk a little bit about your use
the term symbolic in symbolic cognitive
yes so the um the causal theories that
um each that the the robot discovers and
I have to say uh its mind is a society
of cognition actors and each cognition
actor will want to develop a causal
Theory to predict what it will observe
next in its own limited umelt those
causal theories are essentially logic
programs that it discovers uh I will
observe C if I've I'm observing A and B
for example
um so uh much of the learning done by
the robot are are captured as either
um logic programs which are symbolic or
and or as uh beliefs which are also
uh uh symbolic
predicates so uh the the the world view
that the robot develops internally
intrinsically is expressed symbolically
as these logic programs and and these
predicates thus
symbolic in what
language ah the uh I use two programming
languag
for the the symbolic
processing uh and discovery of of of of
U caal theories I use prologue which is
very well suited uh to uh State uh to to
express uh State search
problems uh search space uh problems and
to solving them and I use a functional
Pro language called lexer to implement
uh perception and and action basically
interfacing with the robots percept uh
sensors and uh actuators prologue in
Elixir thank you all
right as we head into the last part of
the Stream So if anyone has questions
from live chat they can write it
otherwise I
will make some notes on one slot
and then anyone who wants to bring up
anything or ask anything or or anything
that they're excited about for the
second half the year or however they can
go for it so um in the hour before this
stream ends ands on the verge of a loss
of nothing to share I just brought in
some pictures from the prior weeks and
wanted to open this space and have the
time of reflection and this multiscale
self and multiscale time and space
Concepts and just where have we been
we're in the round table where are we at
where are we heading and then where when
how Etc is active inference on that and
and just a few of The Adventures of the
last week well first where where were we
in the
last end of the last round table and
here we had these multiple
Horizons and what was happening in
active inference and what we could be
doing
and a a visit
to host archival
materials and a visit to view Bucky
Fuller's archive
materials both really impressed upon me
the the relevance and necessity of
documentation archiving
intergenerational culture contact and
many more things and this was a funny
picture taken from a diner we deliver
Norms but we don't only deliver Norms
we're also part of them and so on so
that was kind of a funny sign to
see and then just in terms
of where when not traveling where I'm
traveling and how to move into the
next half of the
year so that's all I'll say
there how about just anything people
want to ask or mention for coming
forward I have a question why is your
bike called Red
Queen oh just kind of moving faster and
faster and staying in the same place
anyone want
to add anything or what yeah
Alex yeah I want to say say thanks to
all everyone who participated today and
that's great that we bring back back to
the format of uh
participating bro participants then just
officers and uh it will be great to see
people next rounds so let's
continue actually I had a a quick
question I I used to be much more
involved with the Engineering Group the
RX and fur group and un fortunately had
to sideline my participation with it
have there been any particular ularly
interesting developments recently aside
from the the live live
stream what to say well other than look
at the documents and their
repos
um several things have been leared and
developed kass's work at learnable Loop
and also the developer teams
examples have very rapidly caught up
with the major release 3.0 which was a
somewhat breaking change in the sense
that the prior app models were changed
and didn't work in 3.0 but it's built in
a better way so to see how fast the
developers were able to iterate on the
versioning and then the learning of the
model
building and then to as we start to have
people with more computer science
less more active inference less and
Engineering experience and all this and
and all these different perspectives and
that helps to
disentangle where are the paths that
lead into the analytical details of
message passing how is that being
implemented from what space of ways it
could be implemented so like what's
required by RX and fur and RX
environments what's just a norm of use
emerging Norm of use but not something
required so a lot of this is still being
fleshed out but to see some new types of
models open
source and then just personally like to
be able to take kass' examples copy them
into an online Cloud browser
notebook hit run all reload the Page hit
run all again and have a real drone
active inference simulation schematic
but
educational run in two clicks it's just
something we didn't have one two three
Etc years ago so to be and for that to
be not just a rapper or like a buffer
around a simplified way but that rather
to be an interpretable engineering grade
spec that's just brilliantly abstracted
from the reactive message passing it's a
major Tech
unlock super cool um also bonus points
that uh you can so quickly reproduce the
code uh in your own system or in your
browser and run it that's what I'm doing
for my conference I'm doing everything
in Google collab so that attendees can
just hop in you have a Google account
you can do whatever you want uh I think
that's a great sort of Learning Resource
for for institute members and others too
just keep it keep it ready to go no need
to dig through a ton of uh you know
library archives and subd directories to
finally get the thing
running yeah anyone else want to add or
ask
anything yes since it's my first
Presence at this round table I just like
to uh Express that um how much I
appreciate the openness and and and uh
welcoming nature and the welcoming
nature of the this community it it
really encourages multiple backgrounds
multiple perspectives it it
listens uh and and it speaks in in very
in many voices and I find that it it
really uh
uh promotes true open
science and
it's it's I don't take it for granted it
is rare and I appreciate
it thank you
JF okay
lasts
call okay thank you everyone thanks
everybody joining and looking forward to
see you around so
bye